hello my name is grian and i've got
arrows everywhere welcome back to
hermitcraft we're on episode two after a
very very successful episode one thank
you so much to everyone that watched it
i hope you did enjoy it and hopefully we
can have an excellent second episode as
well so you're probably wondering
where i am what i'm doing who i am oh no
no
this is not the time to no i can't i
can't i can't no no no no no
i literally cannot afford to die i
really really can't i'm so close to
finishing what i'm doing you're probably
wondering what i'm doing where i am
i am in a hole in the desert now i went
all the way out here because
this is where all the sands at and i
need a lot of sand but what i came
across was a bunch of turtles
if you just wait a second i'm going to
get myself to full health and we'll get
out of this hole
what we're here for
is sand mainly
and what i found
was a couple of turtles well more than a
couple i found quite a few
so i have made a very very temporary
base here and i've started breeding
turtles
so let's go have a look this is it this
is this is turtle bay so to speak
and
this is how many eggs i've managed to
get them to to lay however i've got two
two of them stuck in here with me
however
they take
absolutely
ages to hatch and they only hatch at
night
so not only is it the most dangerous
time it is oh it's just it is a
nightmare and
i've had three hatch so far which is why
i've got three scoots i've got a load of
seagrass
and this is like watching paint dry i
really think that the numbers need to be
turned down on this because this is so
dull honestly you have to protect these
turtles or protect these eggs that's why
i've got this cobblestone protection
chamber
and it is just taking forever
really really is like i think it's been
over an hour and a half maybe even two
hours three i don't know how long it's
been i i i have been waiting here for
ages
and i've only got three scoots so i
think
a turtle farm in the future is going to
happen because i don't think anybody can
be bothered to do this at all so while
i've been waiting these extra long
nights i've been gathering sand galore
turning it into glass harvesting
sugarcane making more sand and glass as
you can see i've completely decimated
this area and what i've been doing
is just taking out the sandstone
underneath here and letting it fall on
the on the torches here and then i'm
getting a load of sand
oh
oh no
no no no inside inside inside inside
inside inside um
okay that wasn't scary at all
that wasn't
turtles hello little fellas
ah two of them have finally hatched is
that enough
oh
yeah zombie glio says i have a phantom i
have four yep i also have four
because nobody's been sleeping because
of the whole turtle watch thing i
haven't slept a single night and neither
has anyone else and we all have phantoms
after us
oh my goodness this is not good oh have
you ever heard anything so quite so
terrifying in your life so these guys
will eat the seagrass and when they turn
into big turtles
then that's when we get the scoot
so we just got to keep giving them stuff
now i actually had three of these little
guys hatch and i can't get over how cute
they are i think they're the cutest baby
animal in the entire game
once i had three of these going
they disappeared they dropped their
scoots and they vanished i don't know
whether there's something going on or
what will they will they dive into here
and i can just hit them
oh no they've gone that is really really
scary
really scary
the noise that they make
the fact that you don't see them the way
they fly around
everything about them
is terrifying
oh my goodness and as you can see
i've got myself a cow
this is going to be one of two of my
well the start of my cow farm
let's keep these if we keep these guys
breeding as much as possible
then later on we'll have a room full of
turtles and it should be really easy to
get a lot of the eggs because they're
all born here because all of these
turtles are born here they will then
come back here now once i get silk touch
i can get my hands on these eggs and
then create my own turtle farm yes
that's five scoots and then i can make
my own turtle farm and harvest all of
these
oh my goodness there it is the turtle
helmet and i've got water breathing for
10 seconds i need to try this out
[Music]
oh brilliant
absolutely brilliant uh it turns out i
actually died and i have to get all my
stuff back again but i'm gonna make a
trip back home but i think i've broken
the turtles
i genuinely think i've broken them
i've got loads of these little guys
around again and trying to make them
grow but
it turns out when you've got a lot of
eggs
they don't know where to plant their
eggs or lay their eggs and they kind of
just scuffle around for ages creating a
right mess
look at them go
because this is such a laborious task i
really think there's a lot of money in
this game to be made
from making a decent turtle farm i
really do a scoop farm i love the word
scoot scoot
i think a scoot farm would make a lot of
money on this server so maybe once i've
got myself a bunch of the eggs we'll
make one
all right let's start heading back to
base because it's been a very long
ordeal just setting up this stuff and
you can kind of tell just how long i've
been here by how much sand i've taken by
all the farming i've done but we're
gonna have to make several trips before
we can do anything with that
you okay they're in the back barry
excellent
there we are home sweet home now
for those of you wondering i have this
cow in my boat with me because i want to
start a cow farm
now i obviously need two but i need a
way to get this cow down into the base
and i think i've come up with a genius
way to do it i don't know if people have
already done this and i don't even know
if it's going to work but i'm going to
try it anyway so first thing i need to
do is dive right down here and i'm
actually gonna have to make a quick hole
in my base to get the cow in so let's do
that from the inside
so this is the little space that i'm
gonna make here it's gonna flood very
quickly but that shouldn't be a problem
i'm going to use two doors
right i've got two doors to block the
way i place reeds
i really hope that this works and i keep
placing them
all the way
to the surface
like so
i think everyone knows where this is
going and make a two by two so that we
have a clear way to fall down there we
go now we have a way in
and hopefully this works
maybe i haven't thought this through so
we're gonna take barry down the chute
and hopefully we don't take damage i
think we made it
barry
barry's here
this is genius i could just sail him in
i can just sail him in
i can
hey brilliant
oh absolutely brilliant
well there we are barry's in
barry is oh
excellent now how do i get him out
hey
oh barry
i've never been so happy
now i just need to get you a little
friend and that's what we're gonna go
and do right now
and here is cow number two betsy
oh that took ages i don't know why cows
are so difficult to find
but we did it so
we just need to gently ease our way into
the reed tube
and we fall straight down
and we're in
and
we just uh we just boat our way into the
ship
[Music]
i can't believe that that worked it's
such a simple thing to do but it
actually worked
[Music]
and we blocked them off
we have two cows now we just need to set
up the little quick farm so that i can
get all of the leather and stuff that i
need oh boy that was quite an adventure
now we need to get this cow farm going
don't we betsy and barry or la what was
your name
was it bertie bert but berto barry and
betsy uh we're gonna get a quick farm
going for you guys so that i can get all
the leather and stuff that i need so
we're gonna do one that's really really
easy really really simple
and involves very little effort on my
part and to be honest with you something
like this will probably do me for a very
long time
okay so it's fairly simple there's just
a dispenser here it's gonna have a
bucket of water in it but i actually
need this for the time being we're gonna
coax the cows down here and hopefully
this should work as far as i'm aware and
this will just be a very temporary farm
just to get us started and the idea is
if you don't know this farm design is
that when the water is on
it puts the cows up allowing you to feed
them or whatever and then when they have
baby cows the baby cows come down here
but we don't actually want the baby cows
to come down here just yet and we put a
lever right here above the dispenser
dispensers turned on and we have a
couple of bouncing cows we give them
their love hearts they're gonna breed
and so on and so forth so we need to
just do a few trips of this
now none of this looks particularly good
at the moment
and i was thinking to myself that
our base in particular is really really
small and
i don't really like that i don't like
that at all
let's make ourselves another farm since
we're here
just a very simple one we need to have
ourselves we need to get ourselves some
chickens basically might as well have as
many farms here as possible
okay let's hope we get some chickens one
two
three
four come on
yes two chickens
that's all we need and then we can get
these guys running
no no no no no no
oh i'm such an idiot
oh there's def it's definitely not gonna
give me oh my goodness
okay
i've borrowed some eggs from next door
let's see if we have any luck now
two oh you know what why don't we just
get rid of all of these and there we
have it we have two very awful looking
farms but remember this is just to get
started you're not gonna believe this
you're really not gonna believe this but
i was just mining along i was strip
mining all the way from my base now that
is a really really long tunnel now what
i've been doing is making really long
tunnels and then just turning around
doing this and then doubling back so
there's basically a grid pattern all
across
my strip mine but on this particular one
i just kept mining in a straight line
and you're not gonna believe this i have
come across someone else's base so i
mined this and i saw a chest and i
thought oh a dungeon or something no
this looks like someone else's strip
mine
full of cobblestone
and i don't know where i am exactly but
i'm sure
we can find out whoever's base it is
it's in a direct straight line from my
base
this is mumbo's island this is 100
mumbo's island
i can't believe it
that would mean okay that definitely
means that my base is a straight line
west
that's unbelievable
i don't think i should tell him either
i don't think i should tell him
i know that this is mumbo's island
because i milked his cows and ran away
i don't really know what to do with this
new information that i have i have
direct access to mumbo's island without
having to hop in a boat it is definitely
the longest way to get here but that's
pretty cool i'm gonna go and head right
back to my base though i don't know
whether to just cover it up and just
keep it a little secret for now
yeah let's just
let's keep this as you wanna know what
else is quite funny this was a huge bit
of diamonds right here just before i got
here so he managed to make his little
mine all the way and miss the diamonds
directly underneath tell you what we'll
just cover this up for now i doubt he'll
even notice so if he ever comes down
here and he does destroy this
cobblestone for whatever reason he'll
see that this is green strip mine
accidentally found your base i'm
probably going to use this at some point
maybe even make a quick travel between
us or something because if i got a lot
of ice and made this along here we could
do like a really quick boat thing here i
don't know i sort of pondered on the
idea of creating these tubes where you
could travel quickly between the people
within the futuristic district that's
probably something for another time so a
little bit of an update on what i've
been up to i've created the ugliest room
for some farms
ever
the ocean is right above here which is
an absolute nightmare because not only
is it dripping it means that i can't
make this ceiling any higher so as i'm
going to do the chickens
i'm trying to
get in here but this bits in the way
there we go oh no
oh
no no no no no no
[Music]
okay i'm gonna have to get these cows
back in their hole one two three four
okay i think they're all in so similarly
to what i made in minecraft evolution
i've just made a very simple automatic
wheat farm to try and get started on
getting some materials now all of the
farms that i've made here are literally
going to be just temporary but i'm
probably going to end up using them way
longer than i intend to because some of
the projects that i have in mind for
like the buildings that are going to
have all of my stuff in
they're pretty big so this
these farms although they're ugly
they're probably going to have to be
quite functional
for me to get any use out of them
whatsoever
this is probably my favorite thing about
this cow farm is that they're all in
there you flip this and the hill bounce
up and down boing boing boing boing
boing boing boing boing boing boing
boing boing
this is probably my favorite compact
farm that's ever been invented
[Music]
i don't think that'll ever get old so
now that all the farms are done
it's time to actually do something to
give us a bit more space down there in
the half a shipwreck that i've been
using
so i actually saw a comment on the first
episode that i thought was a brilliant
idea now i'm not entirely sure how it's
going to work because
i think it's going to be quite tough
but it will give us a lot of room and
it's going to take a long time so i
think the best thing to do
is a little time lapse of this
and uh if it doesn't work
well
there's always tnt so the idea behind
this time lapse is to put the shipwreck
inside a glass bottle and i started by
making a circle at the back and making
my way forward and encasing it in glass
i started off with grey stained glass
but i very very quickly ran out of grey
stained glass also guess who has two
thumbs and forgot to turn off chat for
this time lapse
this guy
anyway i really failed the shape of the
bottle and then i ran out of stained
glass i went over to normal glass and
then i kind of ran out of normal glass
and it was just a nightmare which kind
of leads me on to say that
episode 2 was not
what i wanted it to be
i wanted it to be just as fun and epic
as the first episode
unfortunately it's super super hot in
the uk i've really struggled to get
anything done i died a lot because
in really stupid green fashion it got so
hot in my office i left for a bit to
cool down i came back and i died because
i didn't log out like an absolute fall
and i had to go and get all my stuff
again and that really interrupted this
video a lot either way it's over now and
hopefully i can make episode 3 better
than this one now i just decided that i
was going to finish this bottle another
time and start clearing out some of the
water using a very interesting technique
using reeds and sand to try and utilize
it as best as i could
anyway
i'm going to cut this time-lapse short
because this is not going the way i
wanted so let's hop back into the game
shall we i have made a real
real mess of this sometimes when you're
building in minecraft things just don't
go the way that you hope they do and i
say this in my tutorials all the time if
something doesn't look right you keep
trying and you keep working on it until
until you get it right and this is
definitely one of those moments
because it is not gone well it has not
gone well at all i think give me enough
time and this could work i could i could
make this work but on the whole
it's not gone well and i've actually run
out of time for today's episode
so i'm actually gonna have to leave it
like this but hopefully by the start of
the next episode this will be at least
cleared out out of the water so we have
a bit of space to work with you'll also
notice that i've had to use two
different kinds of stained glass because
i started using this because it's way
nicer than this one
but it's actually worse because i've now
used just two i've just i've just been a
total idiot and this build has been a
catastrophe absolute catastrophe
i thought i did something clever here
with the reed so i used the reeds along
here as a barrier because you can just
place them under water and then i made a
second barrier here and then i just put
sand in between them and i started
excavating them out which was a great
technique but it doesn't look very good
it doesn't look very good at all
so
all in all today's episode has not been
as good as i would hope and i do
apologize for that i've got a lot of
work to do i've got a lot of learning to
do when it comes to
the technical side of things building in
survival is is a little bit painful
really i've never done a bottle like
this before so this is a new thing and
sometimes my
techniques don't always work out and i
think this is one of those times so if
you take a quick look i haven't finished
i haven't had time
but it looks awful and i think half of
that is because
it's it's only half finished to be
honest with you but
i had to make it shorter because if you
see there that's the half of the ship
and i don't think i'm gonna have enough
space to make the full shipwreck i can
try and try and fit it in but i just
don't think it's going to happen i've
had to make these ugly air pockets
underneath everywhere
and
there is one thing that i'm a little bit
proud of but it's nothing nothing major
at the end of the bottle which has no
shape here i really struggled underwater
to see what's going on it's this bit i
used some stripped oak log to make a
cork in the bottle because it actually
does look like cork but the mixture of
the glass has been bad so
i'm gonna have to get some proper dye
farm going but i just want to get
something i want to get a base rolling
because
i just i need more space to do stuff and
i just yeah i need i need to get
cracking on everything so my idea was to
have this shipwreck in a bottle
underneath which i actually took from a
comment it was a brilliant idea i have
just failed to execute this very well at
all sort of a half finished project i
think if you give me enough time it'll
look alright but for now it won't
so that's it for me everyone i hope you
enjoyed the second episode of
hermitcraft we have made a
lovely little cow farm uh a wheat farm a
chicken farm and we even went and made a
turtle farm but we're gonna eventually
move that over back here
where we can do stuff with it and once
this bottle is done and i have more
space to work with then we can start
working on the proper fuel oh no
that could have been so much worse
i've got to be careful
i'm so sick of water i'm so sick of it
well that's it for me everyone i hope
you enjoyed this video and good
bye